Mom...
Kayo!
Where the hell have you been these past few days?!
You little...
You two!
I should've known you two were behind this!
How could you hide someone else's child?!
You got me needlessly concerned!
I'll sue you for this!
Did you look for Kayo at all
over the past three days?
What? Are you making me out to be the bad guy?!
Screw you!
Kayo?! Let go of me, you idiot!
"Needlessly concerned"?
The only thing you're concerned about is yourself.
What?!
Damn it!
What do you think you're doing,
Kayo?! Let go of me!
Why aren't you listening to me?
Enough, Hinazuki-san.
Kayo-chan doesn't want to see you like this either.
Look who's talking! You're treating me
like a villain in front of my own daughter!
And after you kidnapped her, too!
Who do you think you are?!
Shut up!
You deserve it for locking her in a shed and
not caring when she goes missing for three days!
You've no idea about the pains
and responsibilities of parenting,
so don't run your mouth, you brat!
Go to—
You are Hinazuki Akemi-san, yes?
We are from Ishikari City Hall's
Child Welfare Center.
We've come to talk to you
about your daughter, Kayo-chan.
You set me up! Damn the both of you!
We thought we couldn't get you
to meet us by ourselves,
so we asked Fujinuma-san for help.
Who said I wouldn't meet you?
Oh, my apologies.
Sorry we asked you to do this.
Don't be, Yashiro-sensei.
I wanted to give her a piece of my mind,
so I'm actually glad to be of help.
They're the ones who kidnapped my daughter!
Hurry up and call the police!
No, we first need to discuss your usual
relationship with your daughter.
What're you even talking about?
What's wrong with how I treat Kayo?
We've decided that your daughter, Kayo-chan,
needs to be taken into custody.
Custody?! I'm her legal guardian!
But you didn't even try to look for her
when she went missing for three days.
That's child negligence!
But it was all that brat's fault!
Why am I being treated like a criminal?!
Now, now, Hinazuki-san.
Please calm down.
Fine, then!
I'll go to the police myself!
They can settle this!
Come, Kayo!
W-Wait.
We need to talk!
Hinazuki-san!
Please calm down!
S-Sensei...
Come on! Quit dragging your feet!
Kayo!
I said come on!
Akemi.
Akemi, my girl.
Mom?
Forgive me.
We've been estranged ever since
I made you split up with that man,
but I've been worried about you two the whole time.
I know better than anyone how hard
it is for a single mother to raise a child.
You must've been so lonely.
It must've been so hard on you.
I should've helped you...
But I made you...
shoulder it all yourself.
Please, this is all my fault.
Please don't think badly of Akemi.
Mom...
Mom!
Those tears were probably born out of self-pity.
It seemed like Kayo was
avoiding looking at her mother
because she wasn't someone
she could cling to and cry on.
Akemi, my girl. Don't worry about Kayo.
I promise to take good care of her.
My child is the most important thing
in my life. He means the world to me.
I'm sure you must've felt the same at some point.
Thanks, Sensei.
No need. You're the one
who got us into gear, Satoru.
There's no way we could let your
courageous efforts end in tragedy.
Kayo will be all right now.
I hardly have any memories of my father...
I wonder if this is how a father's words sound.
Thanks, Satoru.
For getting me out of here.
Shall we go, then?
"The Town With Only Me Erased," by Hinazuki Kayo.
When I grow older, old enough
to go wherever I want by myself,
I want to go to a faraway country.
I want to go to a faraway island.
I want to go to an island with nobody around.
I want to go to an island
with no sorrow or suffering.
On that island, I'll climb a tree when I want,
swim in the ocean when I want,
and sleep when I want.
When I think about the town from which
I've been erased, I feel lighthearted.
I want to go far, far away.
I finally managed to save Kayo.
I made sure her life would last far into the future.
From here on, Kayo will walk down her own path.
I believe that a bright future lies ahead of her.
Satoru's been like this all day. Is he gonna be okay?
He's a hero for saving Hinazuki,
but look at him now...
Hey, Satoru-kun. Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You don't look fine at all.
Can ya blame him? Hinazuki's gone.
Yeah. All's well that ends well, though.
Satoru.
Come with me for a sec.
I think Kayo's mother will have to
stay away from her for a few years.
Which means Kayo's going to start
a new life with her grandmother.
Thank you, Sensei.
Oh, no need for—
That's not what I'm talking about.
You said you couldn't let my
courageous efforts end in tragedy.
Those words mean a lot to me right now.
Well, it might be crude to call
that ending a sort of compensation,
but I'd still say your actions merited a reward.
Didn't you want to see Kayo smile?
Looks like I get my reward as well.
By the way, Satoru,
was Kayo at your place the entire time?
No, at a hideout.
A hideout?
Yeah. We hid Kayo in a bus the Izumi Elementary
ice hockey team wasn't using anymore.
So only kidnappers like you would go there, huh?
Y-Yeah...
If that's a joke, it ain't funny.
Now that Kayo's gone, the killer's targets
are down to Hiromi and Nakanishi Aya.
Right now, I have to make sure
neither of them are left alone.
Just like with Kayo.
Hiromi's one thing, since he's my classmate,
but Nakanishi Aya goes to Izumi Elementary
next door, so it'll be hard to approach her.
Apparently she's often with Yuuki-san,
but how am I supposed to talk to her?
She has no clue who I am.
This is going to be pretty difficult.
How to become friends
with someone you don't know?
Just go up and ask them to be your friend.
As if that'd work—
You're thinking, "As if that'd work," aren't you?
Is she psychic?
You've already got Kayo-chan,
but your eyes are wandering, huh?
H-How did you know that?
It was just a bluff.
Well, okay, it is a girl... She's always by herself.
You won't get anywhere with that attitude.
Focus on a positive outcome.
As they say, nothing ventured, nothing gained.
I need to stop by somewhere.
You guys are going to the kids' center, right?
Yeah.
I'll meet you there, then. Laters.
Laters!
So she gets out of cram school at 6:30 p.m.
I can walk Hiromi home
and still get back here in time.
First I need to figure out what they do every day.
Nakanishi Aya's daily routine was simple.
If she were to be kidnapped,
it'd most likely happen at this time,
right after she's let out of cram school.
Satoru!
Am I ever glad to see you! Give me a hand here!
You just had to show up when I wanted
to follow her and see where she lived.
Why would you buy so much stuff at once?
What could I do? It was on sale.
It's so heavy.
Don't say it out loud. It'll only make it feel heavier.
It'd be heavy even if I kept my mouth shut!
You're a lifesaver, Sensei.
Mom went overboard shopping.
Did not!
Say, Sensei...
Why aren't you married?
Wh-Where did that come from?
Listen, Satoru. You can only
get married if you have a partner.
Then they need to be ready for it,
and the time's got to be right... It's complicated.
No, maybe I'm being too cautious because
of a painful experience I've been through.
I'm sorry.
Don't worry about it.
I didn't mind answering that question.
I was actually gonna ask you a different question.
How to approach a girl you don't know?
Yeah. I know her, but she doesn't know me.
Well, I'm the cautious type,
so I'd start by making her less wary of me,
even if it meant beating around the bush.
Make her less wary?
Yeah. In other words, show off your good side.
Like, if you're good at sports
or cooking. Use whatever you can.
The moment she takes an interest in it,
she'll let her guard down.
Don't be too impressed.
I'm not good at expressing my
feelings directly, so I just rely on logic.
Something's sticking out.
Don't touch that, Satoru!
I-I'm sorr—
This is...
You caught me, Satoru.
Candy?
Now that you've seen it,
no point in hiding it anymore!
You eat some too! Become my accomplice!
Ever since I quit smoking three years ago,
candy has been my go-to substitute.
When I'm by myself, I can't relax without it.
Wh-What a weirdo.
Thanks.
Gimme one too.
Here.
I'm gonna go do my homework at the kids' center.
Okay.
Wait, Hiromi. I'll go with you.
First Hinazuki, and now it's like
you're Hiromi's guardian.
Y-You think?
Can we talk in private, Satoru?
Sure.
Sorry, Hiromi. I'll join you later.
Got it.
What's really on your mind, Satoru?
I saw how determined you were
to save Hinazuki at all costs,
but everything went well,
so what's wrong with you now?
If something's bothering you,
could you tell me about it?
I can't really explain it. It's too far-fetched.
I wanna dig deep and take a step forward like you.
I wanna become a superhero, too.
If there's another part to this, take me with you.
What do you make of these footprints, Kenya?
An adult's been through here.
Not just that. Take a closer look.
I think they had their shoes wrapped in cloth.
It wasn't to prevent them from slipping, was it?
Probably to avoid leaving distinctive footprints.
The backpack's gone.
So's the box with the briquettes.
I think there are fewer boxes in general.
A lot of torn up cartons, too.
Somebody must've taken the contents with them.
What's your point, Satoru?
Do you remember the man who supposedly
showed up late at night when Kayo was here?
Yeah. The guy who left a backpack
full of sketchy stuff here, right?
I'm pretty sure he's a murderer
who's targeting children.
What are you talking about, Satoru?
I know that this sounds unbelievable.
What makes you so sure?
I can't give you a proper explanation right now.
When I saw the backpack and the briquettes,
I thought that this was a hiding place
for a serial killer's murdering tools.
Even I know that it sounds crazy.
But that's how I feel.
I'll tell you now since it's all over.
The whole Kayo thing? Preventing
her mother's abuse was only part of it.
I wanted to protect her from this murderer.
That's why I didn't want to leave her alone.
Do you aspire to become a detective
or a novelist when you grow up, Satoru?
The issue isn't whether what
you're saying is too far-fetched or not.
It's whether I believe you or not.
You don't have to walk me this close to home.
I'll be fine. I'm a boy, you know.
It's fine. I had something to do here, anyway.
Satoru-kun...
What?
I want to believe you too.
I'll do everything I can,
so tell me if you ever need help, okay?
Of course.
See ya!
Laters!
See you tomorrow!
Honestly, Satoru, 99 percent of me
thinks your theory couldn't possibly be true.
But the other one percent thinks
it's not completely out of the question.
Yeah. From the outside, it probably looks like
I'm playing detective, making up crimes—
Playing detective is fine by me.
It might be because of
what's been happening lately,
but I think that we should let your feelings guide us.
You believed in me and
gave me your side of the story.
So I want to do my part and believe in you too.
It's for my own sake that I want to trust you.
Similar to someone wanting to be trusted,
but the other way around.
Thanks, Kenya. Thanks, Hiromi.
I could've saved her!
18 years ago, I think I said
those words to my mother and cried.
I never want to go through that again.
I won't leave anybody alone.
I can save them!
Remember to get your parents
to fill out that handout!
Okay!
I want you to come with me somewhere.
Satoru, wanna hit up the hideout now?
Sorry, we've got something to do.
See you later, then.
Laters.
Oh, okay.
Laters...
What're they sneaking around for?
They're no fun.
Wanna follow them, then?
Sure.
Let's go!
Okay!